Hi
Hi.
我是Ricardo
I'm Ricardo.
我来自Google Play团队
I work on the Google Play team.
我将要和你分享Developer Console中
I'm going to tell you about all the tools
一些可获取的工具
available in the Developer Console
以帮助你在Google Play上创造出高质量的应用
to help you build high quality apps for Google Play,
从应用发布过程中的小建议
from tips in the publishing process,
再到如何去做适合你自己的数据报告
to how to make the best of the data reporting available to you.
让我们从最基本的开始  正确的定位受众
Let's start from the basics-- targeting the right audience.
首先  前期的一些市场调查和目标群体评估
First, it's a good idea to do a bit of market research
是一个好主意
and assess your target audience.
了解你将要定位的
Understand and what and what versions and screen sizes
受众的系统版本以及屏幕尺寸
you want to target.
如果你访问developer.android.com
If you go to developer.android.com
找到Dashboard一栏  你会看到相关的数据图表
and search for dashboards, you can get relevant graphs
向你展示了你该支持哪个版本
to show you which versions you would want to support.
那里你也能得到更好的答案  如果你开始想设计一款
You're likely to get the best result, if you design your app
可以在平板上运行的应用的话
to work on tablets from the start.
平板上不断攀升的屏幕面积
The increased screen area on tablets
给了你无限的可能
gives you more possibilities and allows
并且让应用和用户有着更多的互动
for more engagement with the user, which
意味着会有不断增加的使用率以及更多盈利的机会
can mean increased usage as well as more monetization opportunities.
如果你想开发一款游戏应用的话
If you're building a game, make sure you
请确保在最近添加到Google Play中的18种游戏分类的里面
choose the right category among the 18 new game
选择正确的分类
categories recently added in Google Play.
在理顺完应用的要点以及定位之后
After sorting out the general outline and placement
是时候开始动手开发它
of your app, it's time to start building it.
但是无须等到应用开发进度完成100%时
But don't wait until your app is 100%
才推送给用户
finished before showing it to people.
我们为开发者提供了Beta版测试
We have designed beta testing to help
以帮助开发者能够尽快的得到用户反馈
you get user feedback as early as possible.
在应用尚未正式面世之前
Before your app is ready to be seen by the world,
你可以先将应用推送至你安排好的用户测试组
you can distribute it to a group of users you select.
我们称之为Alpha和Beta版测试组
We call this alpha and beta test groups.
若你的应用尚未发布正式版本
If you don't yet have a production version of your app,
除了那些已经在测试组里面的用户
your app will be invisible in Google Play,
你的应用在Google Play上是不可见的
except to the testers you choose.
如果你正在使用Google Play游戏服务
If you're using Google Play Games Services,
你也可以通过Alpha和Beta版测试
you can use the alpha and beta testing
来测试你的游戏服务
to test your game services as well.
你可以利用Google网上论坛或者是Google+社群
You can use Google groups or Google+ communities to indicate
将你希望加入Alpha和Beta版测试组的人员添加到其中
which users you want to be able to access the test versions
of your apps.
你可以为每个应用版本以及测试人员
You can set a what's new field for each version of your app,
都设定不同的组别
including the ones for testers.
而这就能有效的告诉你的测试人员
And this is really useful to tell your testers what's
他(她)们将要收到的Alpha或者是Beta版应用都有哪些新特性
new in the alpha and beta versions they are about to receive.
每位用户都有选择成为每个应用的测试人员
Each user will need to opt in to be a tester for each app
卸载也同样如此
and unload the app of course.
为了帮助用户成为测试人员  大多数开发者一般会提供一些网页
To aid users in doing so, many developers create a little web
上面有一系列提供给测试者的相关指导说明
page with a set of instructions that they send out
或者是在Google+测试组的社群进行相关提及
to their testers, or mention it in their group or Google+ community.
在进行Alpha和Beta版测试过程中
Now that your alpha and beta test is in progress.
Alpha或者是Beta版的测试人员
It's good to know that users who are alpha or beta testers
是无法对你的应用进行相关评价的
cannot leave reviews for your app.
通过这种方式  可以有效的保护你的新版应用
In this way, you can protect against leaks
防止信息泄露和被恶意刷评
about your secret app or harm to your ratings
如果你的Beta版本仍有一些bug存在的话
if you're beta version still has some bugs.
你仍旧可以在Developer Console中查看相关数据统计
However, you can still see crash reports, optimization tips,
以及应用优化建议和崩溃报告
and statistics in the Developer Console.
它把隶属于不同Alpha和Beta版测试组的结果
And we explicitly mark out results
明确的标记出来
that pertain to your alpha or beta test.
举个例子  你可以快速地把所有Beta版测试人员
So for example, you can quickly isolate all application crashes
在测试过程中的应用崩溃报告分离开来
that your beta testers are experiencing.
你的Beta版测试人员更有助于
Your beta testers are great for identifying
帮你发现bug和易用性问题
bugs and the usability problems.
但是请务必注意  他(她)们并不能代表
But keep in mind, they are not a representative sample
所有的应用受众用户
of your target user population.
一旦你的应用经过了好几轮的测试
Once your app is looking good to your beta testers,
并且在Beta版测试用户的圈子里普遍反响不错
and it has been through a full round of testing on your side,
那就是时候正式发布了
it's time to publish.
在应用正式发布给所有用户以后
Once your app is published to all users,
当你推出你的下一个更新之时  你会有些选择的余地
you will have some options when you roll out your next updates.
在Google
Here at Google.
我们希望每次推出新版本应用的更新
We want to be sure that everything goes well when we
都能如愿以偿的正常运行
roll out new version of our apps.
我想你也是这样想的
And we know that you do as well.
为此  我们推出了分阶段发布的方式
For this, we design staged rollouts.
你可以向一定比例的用户提供应用更新
You can rollout updates of your app
比如说5%
to just a percentage of your users, like 5%,
然后随着时间的推移
and then crank it up to 100% when
你发现反馈一切良好  并且没出现什么问题
you can see that the reviews are still good,
可以将比例增大至100%
and there are no problems on the horizon.
不必惊慌失措  即使你意识到推出了糟糕的版本
Don't panic, if you realize that you rolled out a bad version
在分阶段发布模式仍旧运行的时候
while a staged rollout is still in progress.
修复问题之后  发布一个全新版本即可
Spin up a bug fix and publish a new version.
新的版本将会取缔用户之前安装的糟糕版本
Your fix will go out to the users who have the bad one,
然后你可以恢复分阶段发布
and you can resume the rollout.
至此  我们已经讨论完了应用的发布过程
Now that I covered the publishing process, let's focus
让我们开始专注于监视应用的动向
on monitoring how your app is doing.
我们认为开发者在洞察用户
Here at Google we think that the developers do best
以及专注于应用性能方面做的很棒
when they have lots of insights into their users and app performance.
大多数成功的开发者告诉我们说
Most successful developers tell us
他(她)们每天都登入Developer Console
that they log into the Developer Console
检视应用基本统计和各种反馈
every day to check on their statistics, reviews,
以及优化建议
and optimization tips.
这是由Developer Console提供的
Here's an overview of some of the types of data
一些数据类型的概览
that is offered in the Developer Console
我们希望更多的开发者都该看看它
that we think more developers should be looking at.
从最基本的开始
Starting from the basics, most of you
你可以在Developer Console看到
know that you can see installs and the uninstalls
指定日期范围内的安装以及卸载量
over time in the Developer Console.
除此之外  如果你到统计页面
In addition to that, if you just go to the statistics page,
你可以看到应用一定时间范围内的评分情况和崩溃趋势
you can see how your app ratings have changed over time, crash
前提是在你把Developer Console账户
trends and if you link your Developer Console
和Google Analytics帐户关联起来之后  活跃的用户数据
account with Google Analytics, data about your active users,
以及互动情况全都一目了然
and their engagement with your app.
别忘记点击App version
Be sure to click on app version to make
以确保能进行新的应用版本和旧版本的对比
sure you compare your new versions against the older ones.
也可以使用导出统计信息为CSV格式的方法
Also use the CSV exports to download the full data set
将更多的数据导出
beyond the first top 10 values.
如果你是一名游戏应用开发者并且使用Google Play游戏服务的话
If you're a game developer and you use Google Play Games
通过新游戏统计模块
Services in your app, you can monitor your game performance
你可以时刻监视着游戏的相关表现以及关键的玩家指标
and key player metrics using the new game stats module
这也是我们几周前上线的新功能
that we just launched a few weeks ago.
应用崩溃是一个重要问题
Crashes can be a major problem.
它们会令用户感到沮丧和不满
They make users unhappy and dissatisfied.
也可以导致应用收到一系列的差评
They can result in bad reviews and users
让用户在沮丧中卸载掉开发者的应用
uninstalling your app in frustration.
所以我们花了大量的时间让Developer Console中的
So we have spent time making the crash reporting feature
崩溃报告机制变得更加完善
in the Developer Console even better.
你可以查看Beta版测试组以及分阶段发布中的崩溃报告
You can check on your beta test and your stage rollout
通过筛选系统版本的方式
by filtering your crashes by version.
你也可以了解这些崩溃情况
You can also see how these crashes break
是怎样在不同的设备以及系统版本上发生的
down across different devices and Android versions
这使得错误追踪变的异常容易
to make it easier to track down what's going wrong
以及知晓为何用户在某个特定设备上总是怨气重重
or why users on a certain device are complaining.
如果你开发本地代码的话  我们为本地崩溃对应地完善了
If you develop a native code, we have improved the reporting
崩溃报告机制以及表现形式
and presentation, specifically for native crashes,
更好的将相关崩溃加以类聚
with better clustering of similar crashes
同时对相关信息进行总结
and summarizing of relevant information.
而且  崩溃的收集是实时的
Also, remember that we collect crashes in real time,
所以你可以立刻监视应用的阶段发布或者是Beta版本
so you can monitor your staged rollout or beta version
在你正式发布它之后
minutes after publishing it.
最后  相关的优化建议会向你展现
Finally, optimization tips show you new ways
应用可进行优化的新方法  为你的应用以及用户量身订做
that you can improve, tailored to your own apps and users.
从添加翻译  到确保你的应用在平板上工作正常
From adding translations, making sure your app works well
再到确认你的应用所使用的是
on tablets and ensuring your app is using the latest
最新版本的Google services
versions of the Google services you integrate with.
我们也会通过提醒的方式帮助帮助你
We also help you out with alerts,
如果在应用安装卸载  评分以及崩溃方面有什么重大变故
letting you know if there's been a big change in your installs,
提醒机制会及时让你知道
uninstalls, ratings, or crashes.
通过提醒机制  坚信Google
With alerts, you can trust Google to alert you
会在相关事情发生后第一时间通知你
whenever a relevant event occurs.
所以开发者就能得以专注于应用的开发
So you can focus on building your app.
我们也添加了通过电子邮件来接收提醒
We just added the ability to get these alerts over e-mail.
所以请确保在Developer Console的设置中
So make sure you subscribe to this new service
订阅了这项新服务
from the setting section of the Developer Console.
做个总结  让我们简单回顾下开发高质量应用的几个关键方面
To summarize, let me remind you the core aspects in building
首先  研究受众和目标群体
a quality app-- research and identify your target audience,
在应用仍在开发阶段时
collect early feedback by your beta testers
通过Beta版测试人员收集早期反馈
while development is still in progress,
利用分阶段发布模式进行零风险发布
do risk-free releases with stage rollouts,
通过Google Play提供的相关数据
and keep optimizing your app with the data
对应用进行持续的优化
that Google Play makes available to you.
开始行动吧
Now get cracking.